{"sentText": "The central question is where should the Plaintiffs \\ ' claims be tried , in England , as the Plaintiffs contend , or in Spain , as the Defendants contend .", "articleId": 6, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "England", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The Parties : The Kuwait Investment Office -LCB- \\ ` KIO \\ ' -RRB- is a branch of the Kuwait Investment Authority established in Kuwait and has as its function the management of investment of funds belonging to the Government of Kuwait .", "articleId": 9, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Kuwait Investment Authority", "em2Text": "Kuwait", "label": "organization.organization.founders"}, {"em1Text": "Kuwait Investment Authority", "em2Text": "Kuwait", "label": "organization.organization.founders"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Kuwait Investment Authority", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Kuwait", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Kuwait", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "KIO is based in London .", "articleId": 10, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "KIO", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "KIO", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Grupo Torras is incorporated in Spain and is indirectly controlled by KIO .", "articleId": 12, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "KIO", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Spain", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "KIO", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "He was served with the proceedings under RSC Order 11 in the Bahamas ; but the Judge held that he was domiciled in England and could have been served in England .", "articleId": 18, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Bahamas", "em2Text": "England", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Bahamas", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "England", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "England", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Messrs de la Rosa , Soler , Nunez , de Mir and Pique were together referred to as the \\ ` Spanish Defendants \\ ' , being domiciled in Spain .", "articleId": 20, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Mir", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Nunez", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Robinson , Mr Jaffar and Mr Moukarzel were domiciled in England .", "articleId": 27, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Robinson", "em2Text": "England", "label": "people.person.place_of_birth,people.person.nationality"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "England", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Robinson", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Jaffar", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "England", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Jaffar was Deputy Chairman and General Manager of KIO until 20 April 1990 , a director of Koolmees and Kokmeeuw until 15 March 1990 , and at all material times Vice-President and a director of Grupo Torras .", "articleId": 28, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "KIO", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jaffar", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "KIO", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Coll is an accountant of British nationality who lives in Spain .", "articleId": 34, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Coll", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Russell is also an accountant ; he lives in Jersey and practices as a partner of Russell Limebeer .", "articleId": 36, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Jersey", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Russell", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Jersey", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Croesus International Ltd and Wantley Developments Ltd are Gibraltar companies provided by Mr Coll .", "articleId": 38, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Gibraltar", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Gibraltar", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Coll", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Wardbase Developments Ltd -LRB- an English company -RRB- , Oakthorn Ltd -LRB- a Jersey company -RRB- , Westow Ltd and Anslow Ltd -LRB- both Isle of Man companies -RRB- , were provided by or associated with Mr. Russell .", "articleId": 39, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Jersey", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jersey", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 5, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Croesus : In May 1988 Us $ 27.4 million at the request of Mr de la Rosa and Mr Jaffar was transferred by KIO to Grupo Torras .", "articleId": 57, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "KIO", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jaffar", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "KIO", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In September 1989 , Banco Santander , at the request of Torras London , transferred US $ 25 million to Kokmeeuw in \\ ` partial repayment \\ ' of the transfer of US $ 27.4 million to the Republic National Bank .", "articleId": 62, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Republic National Bank", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "US", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Republic National Bank", "start": 5, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "It is then alleged that the payment was concealed by a series of sham documents and transactions , notably a sham loan agreement by Torras London to Croesus , with extensions , a guarantee of the \\ ` loan \\ ' signed by Mr Nunez on behalf of Grupo Torras .", "articleId": 63, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Croesus", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Of the US $ 55 million , $ 7.5 million is said to have been traced to an account in Mr Jaffar \\ 's name in a Bank in Zurich ; smaller sums to companies associated with Mr Russell .", "articleId": 71, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Russell", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Bank", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Zurich", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Bank", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Zurich", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Bank", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Bank", "em2Text": "Zurich", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "US", "em2Text": "Zurich", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Jaffar", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Bank", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Zurich", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "As to the US $ 50 million , $ 10 million is said to have been traced to Mr Jaffar \\ 's Zurich Bank , $ 22.5 million to an account controlled by Sheikh Fahad in a bank in London and $ 15.49 million to the account of a company in Jersey of which Mr Russell is a signatory and whose address is the same as Russell Limebeer .", "articleId": 72, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "London", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Russell", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Russell", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Jaffar", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "London", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 5, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Pincinco : Under a Fiduciary Agreement dated 2 October 1990 , Torras London through Banco Santander -LRB- Suiza -RRB- SA deposited US $ 300 million with Bankers Trust AG , Geneva and the latter agreed for a fee/commission of $ 2.1 million to make , and did an 3 October 1990 make , a loan of US $ 300 million to Pincinco at Torras London \\ 's risk and expense .", "articleId": 74, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Geneva", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Geneva", "start": 5, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 6, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Pincinco is a Jersey company now in liquidation of which Mr Russell was company secretary and now a liquidator .", "articleId": 75, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Jersey", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jersey", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The US $ 300 million was not intended to be repaid by Pincinco from its own funds and was not paid to Pincinco for the benefit of Grupo Torras or Torras London .", "articleId": 81, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "London", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "2 billion was transferred by Grupo Torras to Torras London in Barcelona and then by Torras London to an account in the name of Wardbase in London .", "articleId": 88, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Barcelona", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Barcelona", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 5, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "We find it difficult to see how it could properly have been argued at such length that there was no serious issue to be tried : -LRB- See Seaconsar v. Bank Markasi -LSB- 1994 -RSB- 1 AC 438 at p. 455 , where Lord Goff of Chieveley indicated that the issue of the merits should net be debated at length -RRB- .", "articleId": 106, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "AC", "em2Text": "Chieveley", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "AC", "em2Text": "Goff", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Chieveley", "em2Text": "Goff", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "AC", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Goff", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Chieveley", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The Defendants argued that , for the purposes of Article 21 , the parties to these Spanish criminal proceedings included Sheikh Fahad and messrs Jaffar , de la Rosa , de Mir , Nunez , Folchi and Soler .", "articleId": 120, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Mir", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jaffar", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "On 19th May these proceedings were amended to add as plaintiffs messrs de la Rosa , de Mir , Nunez , Folchi and Soler and to claim declarations of regularity in relation to -LRB- among other things -RRB- the four transactions which by then were the subject of the English action .", "articleId": 125, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Mir", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Rosa", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Thus it was argued that England was not an appropriate forum and that Spain was the appropriate forum .", "articleId": 131, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "England", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Chronology As previously stated , the application of these Articles requires that the court determine whether or not it is the court first seized , it is therefore helpful at the outset to list the dates upon which steps were taken in the relevant actions , this action in England and the criminal , guerelJa , proceedings and the Quail action in Spain .", "articleId": 229, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "England", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "9/6/92 Original Quail proceedings filed 26/1/33 Judge Moreiras orders the no-admission of the criminal proceedings on the application of Mr de la Rosa -RRB- 19/2/33 Judge Moreiras confirms non-admission of the criminal proceedings -LRB- `` after further intervention by Sheikh Fahad and Mr Jaffar 14/4/93 English writ issued 15/4/93 English writ served within jurisdiction on Jaffar , Robinson , Moukarzel , Coll & Co. and Wardbase 7/5/33 Missing documentation lodged by Quail in original Quail proceedings 12/5/33 Original Quail proceedings admitted 17-8/5 / 93 English writ served on Anslow , Westow , Croesus , Wantley , Russell , Limebeer and Oakthorn 1P/5/93 Quail proceedings amended by adding de la Rosa , de Mir , Nunez , Folchi and Soler 21/5/93 -15 / 6/93 English writ served on Russell , Sheikh Fahad , Riquel and Coggia 18/6/93 Amended Quail proceedings admitted 21/6/93 English writ served on de la Rosa , de Mir , Soler , Coll and Folchi 3/7/93 Criminal proceedings again not admitted 1/10/93 Amended Quail proceedings served on Grupo Torras 1/10/93 English writ served on Pique 15/11/93 English writ served on Nunez 11/2/34 Audiencia National orders that the criminal proceedings be admitted -LSB- 29/4/34 Judge Foncillas stays the Quail proceedings pending the resolution of the criminal proceedings -RSB- The Expert Evidence of Spanish Law : A vast amount of evidence of Spanish law was adduced before the Judge .", "articleId": 230, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Croesus", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Anslow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Coll", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Russell", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Anslow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Coll", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Croesus", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Anslow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Coll", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Rosa", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Coll", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Anslow", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Rosa", "em2Text": "Coll", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Rosa", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Rosa", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Rosa", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Rosa", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Westow", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Coll", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Westow", "em2Text": "Jaffar", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Westow", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Westow", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Jaffar", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Mir", "em2Text": "Robinson", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jaffar", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Jaffar", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Robinson", "start": 5, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Anslow", "start": 8, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Westow", "start": 9, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Croesus", "start": 10, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 12, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Rosa", "start": 14, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 15, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 16, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Russell", "start": 19, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Rosa", "start": 22, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 23, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Coll", "start": 25, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 27, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "However , where the evidence of an expert witness on foreign law is not contradicted , the Judge should be reluctant to reject it : -LRB- Sharif v Azad -LSB- 1967 -RSB- 1 QB 605 per Diplock LJ at p. 616B -RRB- .", "articleId": 245, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Azad", "em2Text": "Sharif", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Sharif", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Azad", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "But it should be extremely reluctant to substitute its own views where questions of credibility are concerned , since the Judge has had the benefit of seeing and hearing the witnesses : -LRB- Parkasho v Singh -LSB- 1968 -RSB- P 233 at p. 250 ; Dalmia Dairy Industries Ltd v National Bank of Pakistan -LSB- 1978 -RSB- 2 Lloyds 233 per Megaw LJ at p. 286 -RRB- .", "articleId": 247, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "National Bank of Pakistan", "em2Text": "Singh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Singh", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "National Bank of Pakistan", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "It is accepted that his reason under -LRB- iv -RRB- can not stand and that it is still necessary to consider as between the parties common to both the criminal proceedings and the English action - Grupo Torras , Sheikh Fahad and Messrs de la Rosa , de Mir , Nunez , Folchi and Soler - whether Article 21 applies .", "articleId": 254, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Mir", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "That case concerned the carriage on the vessel , the `` Tatry '' , of various consignments of soya bean oil which had been discharged at Rotterdam and Hamburg contaminated , it was said , by diesel oil .", "articleId": 305, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Rotterdam", "em2Text": "Hamburg", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Rotterdam", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hamburg", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Although it is accepted that the reasoning of Mance J can not , as such , stand with the judgment of the Court in Maciej Rataj , the arguments of the Respondents before us are substantially to the same effect and would , if accepted , lead to the same conclusion .", "articleId": 349, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Maciej Rataj", "em2Text": "Court", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Court", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Maciej Rataj", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The Application of Article 21 , the Quail Action : For the purposes of Article 21 , the proceedings which are relevant are , in England , the present action and , in Spain , the \\ ` Quail \\ ' proceedings .", "articleId": 352, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "Spain", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "England", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Spain", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "After the amendment of the Quail action , the parties who are common to the English action and to the amended Quail action are Grupo Torras and messrs de la Rosa , de Mir , Nunez , Folchi and Soler .", "articleId": 354, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Mir", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Nunez", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The matter was adjourned so that the Plaintiffs could decide whether they wished to continue the action against Mr. Nunez , in which case the Court would have to resolve the dispute as to the interpretation of Article 21 to which we have adverted .", "articleId": 363, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Court", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Nunez", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Court", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "It follows that for the purposes of Articles 21 and 22 of the Convention the Spanish courts did not become seized of the Quail proceedings as between the relevant parties until 1st October 1993 , that is to say , a date after the date upon which the English court had , on any view , became seized of the present action as between the relevant parties , which no longer includes Mr. Nunez and Mr. Pique because of the discontinuance of the action against them .", "articleId": 414, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Pique", "em2Text": "Nunez", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Nunez", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Pique", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Accordingly the ground of appeal which was founded on the submission that as between Grupo Torras and the Quail Plaintiffs , other than Mr. Nunez , that is to say , de la Rosa , de Mir , Folchi and Soler , the Spanish court was the first seized , fails .", "articleId": 426, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Nunez", "em2Text": "Mir", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Nunez", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Mir", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The facts in that case , either proved or assumed , were as follows : Macmillan -LRB- the 11th defendants in one of the present actions -RRB- were a wholly owned subsidiary of Maxwell Communications Corporation plc , a company owned partly by the public and partly by Mr Robert Maxwell and his family ; they had a majority holding in the shares of Berlitz ; those shares were transferred out of Macmillan \\ 's name to Bishopsgate Investment Trust , who were owned and controlled by Mr Maxwell and his family ; and then the shares were pledged to secure the debts of companies in the private ownership of Mr Maxwell and his family .", "articleId": 458, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Maxwell", "em2Text": "Robert Maxwell", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Maxwell", "em2Text": "Macmillan", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Robert Maxwell", "em2Text": "Macmillan", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Macmillan", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Robert Maxwell", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Macmillan", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Maxwell", "start": 6, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Maxwell", "start": 7, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "As commonly happens the contracts were arranged in layers : first there was a contract with a limit of \\ xc2 \\ xa31 million , subscribed by New Hampshire Insurance Company alone ; above that there were a succession of layers up to the following totals - 1988/1989 \\ xc2 \\ xa325 million 1989/1990 \\ xc2 \\ xa335 million 1990/1991 \\ xc2 \\ xa350 million 1991/1992 \\ xc2 \\ xa350 million New Hampshire were the leading underwriters on all contracts , except for the top \\ xc2 \\ xa310 million layers in 1990/1991 and 1991/1992 , which were subscribed only by Chubb Insurance Company of Europe SA .", "articleId": 465, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "New Hampshire", "em2Text": "New Hampshire Insurance Company", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "New Hampshire Insurance Company", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "New Hampshire", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "As has already been mentioned , in some of the Maxwell companies Mr Robert Maxwell and his family held a controlling interest but there was also ownership by the public ; others were owned by Mr Maxwell and his family alone .", "articleId": 472, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Maxwell", "em2Text": "Robert Maxwell", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Robert Maxwell", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Maxwell", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In relation to that year Mr Ward of the Risk Management Department said this in his statement : \\ t \\ tTo the best of my knowledge I did not receive a copy of the Chubb excess layer wording for the subsequent policy year , namely , July 1991/June 1992 .", "articleId": 527, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Ward", "em2Text": "Chubb", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Ward", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Chubb", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "However , we were shown a letter dated 16th January 1991 , to New Hampshire from Miss Godwin of the policy division at Willis Wrightson .", "articleId": 541, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "New Hampshire", "em2Text": "Godwin", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "New Hampshire", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Godwin", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "We can not attribute much , or indeed any , weight to the fact that Mr Ward wrote `` checked & okay '' on the letter , and put the policy in the place where original policies were kept ; those were not circumstances which by inference conveyed acceptance to Chubb , since they did not know of them .", "articleId": 586, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Ward", "em2Text": "Chubb", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Ward", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Chubb", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Phillips in the course of his reply pointed out that it was and remains the pleaded case of the Claimants that the Chubb policy did form part of the contracts .", "articleId": 592, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Phillips", "em2Text": "Chubb", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Phillips", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Chubb", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "How then were they allowed to procure a preliminary issue from Waller J. , and to argue before Potter J. that the Chubb policy did not form part of the contracts .", "articleId": 593, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Chubb", "em2Text": "Potter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Chubb", "em2Text": "Waller", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Potter", "em2Text": "Waller", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Waller", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Potter", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Chubb", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The slips for Chubb in Year 3 and Year 4 had the same description of the insured , with very slight and immaterial variations , as the New Hampshire policies for those years .", "articleId": 689, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "New Hampshire", "em2Text": "Chubb", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Chubb", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "New Hampshire", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "We feel that we are relieved from the need to answer those questions by the authority of the House of Lords , in the passage already quoted from P. Samuel & Co Ltd v Dumas .", "articleId": 695, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "House of Lords", "em2Text": "Dumas", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "House of Lords", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Dumas", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- a p. 510 -RRB- quoted from the judgment of Scrutton LJ in Leon v. Casey -LRB- 1932 -RRB- 2 KB 576 at p. 579 : \\ t \\ tThe origin of the order to ships \\ ' papers goes back to the time of Lord Mansfield .", "articleId": 742, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Casey", "em2Text": "Mansfield", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Casey", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Mansfield", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ tWe now turn to the Niger case , first in the Court of Appeal before Bankes , Warrington and Atkin LJJ .", "articleId": 783, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Niger", "em2Text": "Warrington", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Niger", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Warrington", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ tIn our judgment that must also have been the view of the House of Lords in the Niger case -LRB- 1922 -RRB- 13 Ll.L .", "articleId": 796, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "House of Lords", "em2Text": "Niger", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "House of Lords", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Niger", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LSB- Clause 21 - Cargo gear -RSB- Owners shall maintain the cargo gear of the ship which is as follows : See Clause 55 -LSB- Clause 40 - Blacklisting -RSB- Owners guarantee vessel is neither blacklisted by United Arab Republic , Syria , or any other Arabian State , due to previous calls at Israel , nor blacklisted by US Authorities due to previous calls at Cuba ... -LSB- Clause 55 - Vessel \\ 's description -RSB- ... -LSB- Clause 56 - Bunker -RSB- Vessel to be delivered with about 700mts HFO and about 100 mts MDO , and about Units MDO , and to be redelivered with approx .", "articleId": 887, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Syria", "em2Text": "Israel", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Syria", "em2Text": "United Arab Republic", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Syria", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Syria", "em2Text": "Cuba", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Israel", "em2Text": "United Arab Republic", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Israel", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Israel", "em2Text": "Cuba", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "United Arab Republic", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "United Arab Republic", "em2Text": "Cuba", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "US", "em2Text": "Cuba", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "United Arab Republic", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Syria", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Israel", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Cuba", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "JUSTICE NEUBERGER : INTRODUCTION This is an application by Mr Holland , the liquidator of Harvard Securities Limited -LRB- `` Harvard '' -RRB- , for directions under Section 112 of the Insolvency Act 1986 in relation to certain shares in Australian and United States companies held by Harvard .", "articleId": 988, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "United States", "em2Text": "Harvard", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "United States", "em2Text": "Holland", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Holland", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Holland", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "United States", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n Between 1980 and 1986 Harvard purchased shares in various Australian and US companies -LRB- `` the Australian shares '' and `` the US shares '' respectively -RRB- and sold them on to clients .", "articleId": 991, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n When Harvard purchased a block of Australian or US shares with a view to selling them on to clients in parcels of shares , it was its practice not to register each of the parcel of shares in the name of the relevant client .", "articleId": 993, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "In these circumstances , I think the right basis upon which I should proceed is to assume that such communications as I have seen passing between Harvard and its clients relating to the acquisition , sale and holding of the Australian and US shares are typical , and indeed representative , of such communications passing between Harvard and its clients .", "articleId": 996, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "ANZ accepts that , as against Harvard , it is no more than a mere nominee for Harvard ; ANZ has agreed to be bound by any order which the court makes in these proceedings .", "articleId": 998, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "ANZ", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "ANZ", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The sale would be recorded by Harvard by way of book entry , and the share certificate , in respect of the whole block of shares , would remain in the name and physical possession of ANZ in Australia .", "articleId": 999, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "Harvard", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "ANZ", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Australia", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "They are registered in the name of the English Association of American Bond and Shareholders Limited -LRB- `` the Association '' -RRB- , which accepts that it is a mere nominee for Harvard ; like ANZ in relation to the Australian shares , the Association agrees to be bound by whatever decision the court makes in these proceedings .", "articleId": 1003, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "ANZ", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The share certificates for the US shares were held in London by a bank to Harvard \\ 's order , and are now held at the liquidator \\ 's London offices .", "articleId": 1004, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "London", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "On occasion , Harvard wrote to clients `` regarding your purchase of -LSB- certain US -RSB- shares '' and stated that `` in order to save on transaction costs these shares are being held to your order under a nominee name '' .", "articleId": 1009, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Harvard similarly wrote to clients referring to the US shares as `` your shares '' .", "articleId": 1010, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n Harvard \\ 's internal records in relation to the US shares were very similar to that relating to the Australian shares .", "articleId": 1010, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "In these proceedings , the liquidator seeks the determination of the court as to whether Harvard or the former clients of Harvard has the beneficial interest in the Australian shares and the US shares .", "articleId": 1017, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Harvard has sufficient US shares and Australian shares to account to all its former clients in respect of their beneficial interests -LRB- if any -RRB- in such shares .", "articleId": 1019, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "I proceed on the assumption that each of the Australian and US companies maintained their share register respectively in Australia and the United States .", "articleId": 1035, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "United States", "em2Text": "Australia", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "United States", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Australia", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "United States", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Accordingly , -LRB- subject to there being any choice of law clause -RRB- , in light of the observations I have quoted from Macmillan , it seems to me that the issue of the beneficial ownership of those shares is to be determined by Australian law : they are registered shares in a company registered in Australia and the share register is , I presume , in Australia .", "articleId": 1037, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "Macmillan", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Macmillan", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Australia", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Australia", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Further , although probably irrelevant in light of Macmillan , the share certificates are physically in Australia .", "articleId": 1038, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "Macmillan", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Macmillan", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Australia", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Accordingly , I conclude that the US shares are negotiable in equity , and , following the majority view in Macmillan , any question concerning equitable interests in the shares is governed by English law , subject again to any choice of law clause .", "articleId": 1041, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "US", "em2Text": "Macmillan", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Macmillan", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "At 142 line 45 to 143 line 3 , Oliver said that the observation -LRB- of Sir John Romilly MR in Pooley - v - Budd -LRB- 1851 -RRB- 14 Beav 34 -RRB- `` that a trust was created of unascertained goods '' could not `` stand today in light of the decision of the Court of Appeal in Re Waif .", "articleId": 1082, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Oliver", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Oliver", "em2Text": "Pooley", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Oliver", "em2Text": "Budd", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Court of Appeal", "em2Text": "Pooley", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Court of Appeal", "em2Text": "Budd", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Pooley", "em2Text": "Budd", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Oliver", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Pooley", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Budd", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n I now turn to Re Goldcorp Exchange Limited -LRB- in Receivership -RRB- -LSB- 1995 -RSB- 1 AC 74 , a decision of the Privy Council allowing an appeal from the Court of Appeal in New Zealand .", "articleId": 1085, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "AC", "em2Text": "Privy Council", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "AC", "em2Text": "New Zealand", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "AC", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Privy Council", "em2Text": "New Zealand", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Privy Council", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "New Zealand", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "AC", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Privy Council", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "New Zealand", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n After the decision in Goldcorp had been given , the House of Lords refused the defendant in Hunter leave to appeal : see at -LSB- 1994 -RSB- 1 WLR 614 .", "articleId": 1124, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "House of Lords", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "House of Lords", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "House of Lords", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n CONCLUSIONS ON BENEFICIAL INTERESTS IN ENGLISH LAW On behalf of the liquidator , Mr Halpern , to whose argument I am much indebted , suggests that I should hold that the former clients of Harvard have no beneficial interest in the shares in English law , in light of the decision and reasoning in Wait , London Wine , and Goldcorp .", "articleId": 1124, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "London", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "At page 61 of the current , Fifteenth , Edition of Underhill and Hayton `` Law of Trusts and Trustees '' there is strong adverse criticism of the decision and reasoning in Hunter .", "articleId": 1126, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Hayton", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hayton", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Underhill", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hayton", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In addition , as Mr Halpern points out , the reliance by Dillon LJ on the decision in Re Rose appears to overlook the fact that , in the relevant document , Mr Rose had specifically identified the shares which were intended to be the subject matter of the gift -LRB- see towards the bottom of page 500 -RRB- .", "articleId": 1129, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Rose", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Halpern", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Rose", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Underhill and Hay ton conclude their discussion as follows : \\ r \\ n `` In view of the weak reasoning in Hunter - v - Moss and of the ringing endorsement in Re London Wine Shippers Limited by the Privy Council in Re Goldcorp Exchange Limited .", "articleId": 1130, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Moss", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Underhill", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Moss", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n As to Hunter being per incuriam , Mr Halpern argues that it is inconsistent with the reasoning in London Wine and Wait .", "articleId": 1133, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Halpern", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "London", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "London Wine is a decision of a lower court , and in any event it was expressly considered and distinguished by the Court of Appeal in Hunter .", "articleId": 1134, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "London", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "London", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "On the other hand , Wait was also a decision of the Court of Appeal , and was not expressly referred to , let alone distinguished , by the Court of Appeal in Hunter .", "articleId": 1135, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n Equally , I do not consider that I can hold that Hunter is not binding on the basis that it has been effectively overruled by Goldcorp .", "articleId": 1138, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "First , it appears to me that while the decision in Hunter is undoubtedly binding on me in principle , the decision in Goldcorp , being that of the Privy Council and not of the House of Lords , is not binding on me , and would not have been binding on the Court of Appeal in Hunter .", "articleId": 1139, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Privy Council", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Privy Council", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Privy Council", "em2Text": "House of Lords", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "House of Lords", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Goldcorp", "em2Text": "House of Lords", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Privy Council", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "House of Lords", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In my judgment , therefore , the ground upon which the Court of Appeal in Hunter distinguished London Wine is substantially the same ground upon which Goldcorp can be distinguished from Hunter .", "articleId": 1141, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Halpern \\ 's alternative argument was that Hunter could be properly distinguished from Wait , London Wine and Goldcorp on a ground on which the present case could be properly distinguished from Hunter , namely that Hunter was concerned with an express declaration of trust , whereas the other cases -LRB- including the present one -RRB- are not .", "articleId": 1142, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Halpern", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Halpern", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 5, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "While it is true that this is a point mentioned by Dillon LJ when distinguishing London Wine -LRB- see at 458H -RRB- I have come to the conclusion that it is not a proper ground for distinguishing Hunter from Wait , London Wine and , indeed , Goldcorp and the present case .", "articleId": 1143, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Thirdly , in my view the suggested distinction between Hunter , on the one hand , and Wait and London Wine -LRB- and indeed Goldcorp -RRB- on the other hand is not logically defensible , a view clearly consistent with the general thrust of the observations to which I have referred in Underhill and Hay ton , and in Meagher Gummow & Lehane , referred to below .", "articleId": 1147, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Underhill", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Underhill", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- Indeed in the present case , I have already quoted from correspondence from Harvard to its clients in which Harvard described the holding of Australian and US shares , sold to the relevant client , as being held `` on your behalf '' and `` being your shares '' -RRB- .", "articleId": 1149, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "First , that is a ground which is consistent with Dillon LJ \\ 's reliance on Re Rose -LRB- a case concerned with shares -RRB- and his ground for distinguishing London Wine -LRB- and , by implication , Wait -RRB- which , it will be remembered , he described as being `` concerned with the appropriation of chattels and when property in chattels passes '' .", "articleId": 1150, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Dillon", "em2Text": "London", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Dillon", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Secondly , it is on this basis that the editors of Underhill and Hayton believe that Hunter is explained -LRB- although they regard it on an unsatisfactory basis -RRB- .", "articleId": 1151, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Hayton", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Underhill", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hayton", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Underhill", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hayton", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The description of the sub-contracted grain in Wait , the client \\ 's wine in London Wine , and the customer \\ 's bullion in Goldcorp as `` an unascertained part of a mass of goods '' is quite apt .", "articleId": 1156, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "London", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n In all the circumstances , therefore , it seems to me that the correct way for me , at first instance , to explain the difference between the result in Hunter , and that in Wait , London Wine and Goldcorp , is on the ground that Hunter was concerned with shares , as opposed to chattels .", "articleId": 1160, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "London", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Goldcorp", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Hunter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "London", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Goldcorp", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "Had the correspondence and internal records of Harvard gone one stage further , and identified the share numbers the subject of this arrangement , Mr Halpern accepts -LRB- quite rightly in my judgment -RRB- that the beneficial interest in the relevant shares would have been vested in the client .", "articleId": 1161, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Halpern", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n BENEFICIAL INTERESTS : AUSTRALIAN LAW I have the benefit of a detailed report from Australian lawyers , Mallesons Stephen Jaques -LRB- `` Mallesons '' -RRB- which concludes that , on the facts I have recited , Harvard \\ 's former clients would not , under Australian law , have an equitable interest in any of the Australian shares held by Harvard .", "articleId": 1163, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Mallesons Stephen Jaques", "em2Text": "Harvard", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Mallesons Stephen Jaques", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "In those circumstances , Mallesons conclude that : \\ r \\ n `` In our view it is likely that courts of -LSB- Australia -RSB- would hold that Harvard \\ 's former clients hold only contractual rig -RSB- is against Harvard and hold no equitable interest in the relevant securities held by -LSB- ANZ -RSB- .", "articleId": 1169, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Australia", "em2Text": "Harvard", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Australia", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n CONCLUSIONS ON BENEFICIAL INTERESTS The US shares In light of the decision and reasoning of the Court of Appeal in Hunter , I conclude that Harvard \\ 's former clients acquired the beneficial interest in the US shares which were sold to them , and held on their behalf by Harvard , and that those equitable interests are binding on the liquidators .", "articleId": 1189, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Hunter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Court of Appeal", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 5, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "However , in relation to the US shares , and those Australian shares in which the former clients of Harvard have the beneficial interest , the position is a little more complicated .", "articleId": 1202, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "US", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "However , as recent correspondence which I have seen demonstrates , and as indeed is borne out by Harvard \\ 's reasons for holding the Australian shares in the name of ANZ and the US shares in the name of the Association , this would be a potentially expensive exercise .", "articleId": 1204, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "US", "em2Text": "ANZ", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "ANZ", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "\\ r \\ n In these circumstances , it seems to me that the sensible course to take is that suggested by Mr Halpern , namely to direct that the liquidator can sell the US shares and those Australian shares in which former clients of Harvard have a beneficial interest , and that he should then account to each former client out of the proceeds of sale of the relevant block of shares pro rata to that former client \\ 's holding .", "articleId": 1206, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "Halpern", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Halpern", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Halpern", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 1}
{"sentText": "The main issue is whether former clients of Harvard have the beneficial interest in certain US shares and certain Australian shares sold to them , and held for them , by Harvard ; 2 .", "articleId": 1208, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Harvard", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Harvard", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Harvard", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Under English law , in light of the decision of the Court of Appeal in Hunter , by which I am bound , the US shares and the Australian shares sold to former clients after 14th July 1986 , are held beneficially for Harvard \\ 's former clients ; 5 .", "articleId": 1211, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "US", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Hunter", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "US", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Hunter", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "US", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "As my previous judgment records , the second defendant -LRB- `` Royal Hotel '' -RRB- owns the Royal Hotel , a landmark on the water-front at St. Peter Port in Guernsey .", "articleId": 1216, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Guernsey", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Guernsey", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In the previous action , I considered claims by ICCI and Royal Insurance and counterclaims by Royal Hotel arising out of the fires and the conduct of the potential claims to which they gave rise .", "articleId": 1228, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The basis was that , following the fires , Mr McHugh on behalf of Royal Hotel had on a number of occasions used fraudulent means or devices to promote Royal Hotel \\ 's position and to obtain benefits under the business interruption policy , and that condition 5 of that policy provided for forfeiture of all such benefit in such circumstances .", "articleId": 1230, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- 2 -RRB- Mr McHugh \\ 's purpose and intention in giving the instruction was to manipulate Royal Hotel \\ 's monthly and annual occupancy figures , trading turnover and profits for its 1991/1992 financial year so as to create a more favourable picture of its trading performance if and when it became either necessary or desirable to show management or audited annual accounts to one or other of Royal Hotel \\ 's bankers , Republic National Bank of New York -LRB- Guernsey -RRB- -LRB- `` RNB '' -RRB- and TSB Bank -LRB- Channel Islands -RRB- -LRB- `` TSB '' -RRB- Limited .", "articleId": 1236, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Channel Islands", "em2Text": "Guernsey", "label": "location.location.contains"}, {"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Channel Islands", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Guernsey", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "TSB Bank", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Channel Islands", "em2Text": "TSB Bank", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Guernsey", "em2Text": "TSB Bank", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Guernsey", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "TSB Bank", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Channel Islands", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- 3 -RRB- In compliance with Mr McHugh \\ 's instructions , and as Mr McHugh knew and intended , in or about September 1991 Mr Anquetil produced three invoices in the name of Royal Hotel made out to Consolidator apparently showing accommodation at the hotel let to Consolidator for the months of July , August and September 1991 , although , as Mr McHugh and Mr Anquetil each knew , no such accommodation as was shown in the invoices had been let to Consolidator .", "articleId": 1238, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "As my previous judgment recounts , a similar course of events repeated itself when Mr McHugh instructed Mr Anquetil in or about March/April 1992 to address further invoices to BCS -LRB- another company controlled by Mr Slater whose family trust owns Consolidator -RRB- and when such invoices were in June 1992 created for the months March , April and May 1992 .", "articleId": 1241, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Slater", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Slater", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Following my judgment on 5th July 1996 , Herbert Smith by letter dated 12th August 1996 wrote announcing that ICCI and Royal Hotel had decided to avoid the material damage policy and enclosing draft points of claim identifying as the grounds non-disclosure of the matters summarized in paragraphs -LRB- 1 -RRB- to -LRB- 5 -RRB- above .", "articleId": 1244, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- A -RRB- MATERIALITY It is clear that the knowledge and intentions of Mr McHugh as a director and company secretary of Royal Hotel regarding the matters summarized in -LRB- 1 -RRB- to -LRB- 5 -RRB- are attributable to the Royal Hotel , and that ICCI and Royal Insurance were unaware of the matters when the material damage insurance was renewed in October 1991 .", "articleId": 1247, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 4, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "They adduced evidence from Mr Jack Smith , a former underwriter and later manager with the Commercial Union , who was cross-examined by Miss Bucknall .", "articleId": 1254, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Bucknall", "em2Text": "Jack Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Jack Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Bucknall", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "-LRB- per Lord Mustill at p.538C-D -RRB- In St. Paul at p. 124 the Court of Appeal also interpreted this definition as no different from , and to that extent as expressly approving , part of Steyn LJ \\ 's formulation in the Court of Appeal in Pan Atlantic at -LSB- 1993 -RSB- 1 Ll.R .", "articleId": 1260, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "St. Paul", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "St. Paul", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The question is therefore whether ICCI and Royal Insurance have proved that Royal Hotel \\ 's conduct through Mr McHugh was material to be known to a prudent underwriter when agreeing to renew the present material damage insurance .", "articleId": 1288, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Ms Bucknall cross-examined Mr Smith and Mr Walpole of ICCI by reference to the combined insurance proposal form disclosed by ICG , which could embrace hotel insurance and was itself based on a Royal Insurance form , as well as by reference to various standard forms of proposal which she put to him as being used by the Royal Insurance and other leading companies .", "articleId": 1313, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Bucknall", "em2Text": "Smith", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Bucknall", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Bucknall", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Smith", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION,LOCATION,PERSON"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 4, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 5, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The following statement of the position was thus approved as correct by the Court of Appeal in St. Paul : `` The existence of such a presumption is recognized in the authorities : see Halsbury \\ 's Laws of England vol .", "articleId": 1332, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "St. Paul", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "England", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "St. Paul", "em2Text": "Court of Appeal", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Court of Appeal", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "St. Paul", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "England", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In the present case the relevant hierarchy within ICCI consisted in 1991 of Mr Bray as commercial underwriting assistant , working in a team headed by the commercial controller Mrs Butler , above whom in seniority was Mr Peter Morris , the business manager , and then Mr Peter Walpole , the managing director .", "articleId": 1340, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Peter Walpole", "em2Text": "Peter Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Peter Morris", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Peter Walpole", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Bray also acted as part-time executive assistant to Mr Walpole .", "articleId": 1341, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Bray", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Bray", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Walpole", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Morris has since May 1992 been managing director of Rossboroughs , brokers who acted for Royal Hotel in the placing of the present insurances and the presentation of claims under them .", "articleId": 1345, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Morris", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "His statement records that he met and discussed the matter with both Mr McHugh and Mr Walpole and Mr Bray in or after October 1996 .", "articleId": 1346, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Walpole", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "No evidence was adduced that Mr Morris or Mr Butler would not in fact have been willing to attend court or to give oral evidence by video-link .", "articleId": 1347, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Butler", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Morris", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Butler", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Since Mr Bray only had authority up to only \\ xc2 \\ xa32 million he would anyway have reported on the renewal to Mrs Butler or to Mr Morris direct .", "articleId": 1351, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Bray", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Bray", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Morris", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Morris \\ 's underwriting authority was strictly limited to \\ xc2 \\ xa35 million , but in practice Mr Walpole allowed him flexibility and leeway .", "articleId": 1353, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Morris", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Walpole", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Bray had in April 1991 successfully taken the final set of Chartered Insurance Institute examinations for Associateship and was able to produce before me his copy of the CII textbook `` Property Insurance Risk Assessment and Control '' .", "articleId": 1364, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Bray", "em2Text": "Chartered Insurance Institute", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Bray", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Chartered Insurance Institute", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Although she did not attend for cross-examination , I also accept Mrs Butler \\ 's written statement that she would have referred the matter on to Mr Morris , or to Mr Walpole in his absence .", "articleId": 1369, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Morris", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Walpole", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In his statement Mr Morris says that knowledge that inter-company transactions such as those represented by the Consolidator invoices existed and were fraudulent `` would have had a considerable impact on my attitude towards underwriting the policy '' , that it `` would have raised the question of moral hazard and , as a matter of policy , it would have caused me to discuss the matter with Mr Peter Walpole with a view to agreeing an appropriate course of action '' .", "articleId": 1371, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Peter Walpole", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Morris", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Peter Walpole", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "But I do not consider that Mr Walpole or Mr Morris would at the time have drawn any distinction between an unfulfilled but continuing intention to use dishonestly created accounting figures as and when necessary or desirable in relation to bankers and a situation where they had actually been so used .", "articleId": 1378, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Morris", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Walpole", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Morris", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Thirdly , Mr Walpole gave oral evidence that the population of the Channel Islands is essentially very genuine , sincere and honest .", "articleId": 1384, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Channel Islands", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Walpole", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Channel Islands", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "This evidence contrasts somewhat with his witness statement , where he said that any inference that Royal Hotel was doing so badly that Mr McHugh had caused false documents to be created to misrepresent the truth would have been a considerable concern to him `` particularly in a recession -LRB- October 1991 -RRB- , when there was already growing concern about arson '' .", "articleId": 1386, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "This meant that it used its local presence and appreciation of local conditions , particularly in areas such as weather , to offer lower premiums than United Kingdom companies which tended to treat the Channel Islands as another English county .", "articleId": 1391, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "United Kingdom", "em2Text": "Channel Islands", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "United Kingdom", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Channel Islands", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Fifthly , in December 1992 , during the course of events following the fires , insurers became aware of adverse comments in a DTI report affecting Mr Slater , the individual ultimately behind Royal Hotel and its group , but took no steps to avoid any of the insurances on that ground .", "articleId": 1393, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Slater", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Slater", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Apparently , the report recorded the inspectors \\ ' view that the conduct of Mr Slater and another in and about the prosecution of their bid for Norwest Hoist `` was deplorable and showed scant respect for the responsibilities of directors of public companies and the interests of shareholders '' and the inspectors recommended prosecution of Mr Slater under the Companies Act 1967 ss .", "articleId": 1394, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Slater", "em2Text": "Norwest", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Slater", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}, {"text": "Norwest", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Slater", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The submission can not be accepted , even if attention is confined to dishonest conduct which , under the Code of Conduct of the Bar of England and Wales , requires a pleader to have `` before him reasonably credible material which as it stands establishes a prima facie case '' .", "articleId": 1438, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Wales", "em2Text": "England", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "England", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Wales", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "I heard evidence from Mr Martin Bakes of Herbert Smith , Mr Carter of Royal Insurance and Mr Walpole of ICO .", "articleId": 1479, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Martin Bakes", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Carter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Walpole", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Martin Bakes", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Martin Bakes", "em2Text": "Carter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Martin Bakes", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Carter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Carter", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Martin Bakes", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Carter", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 3, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Walpole", "start": 4, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "I held that up to and including this date insurers did not have full knowledge of the relevant circumstances ; that had been withheld from them by Royal Hotel ; the only representations that insurers could be treated as having made up to that stage were that they did not have full information or a full understanding of the position , that they were anxious to achieve this , that they had wanted to cross-examine Mrs Farnon and Mr McHugh in the arbitration for that reason and that , once it became clear that those witnesses were not to be called , insurers were very likely to assert that there had been fraud to obtain benefit , in the absence of any satisfactory last minute explanation .", "articleId": 1481, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Herbert Smith \\ 's letters dated 12th and 19th October 1993 gave Royal Hotel a last chance to put forward such an explanation .", "articleId": 1482, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In mid-1993 Royal Hotel announced that its directors had concluded that its 1993 accounts should include a prior year adjustment reversing the transactions with BCS , which Royal Hotel \\ 's expert accountant in the business interruption arbitration -LRB- Mr Haberman -RRB- told insurers \\ ' expert -LRB- Mr Lee -RRB- on 6th October 1993 that he suspected had been included in Royal Hotel \\ 's accounts to `` massage '' the figures , though neither he nor Mrs Farnon knew why .", "articleId": 1485, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Haberman", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Lee", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Haberman", "em2Text": "Lee", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Haberman", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Lee", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Haberman \\ 's report dated 5th October 1993 said that he had `` ascertained '' by discussion with Mrs Farnon and Mr McHugh that the rooms charged to Consolidator were occupied by related company employees and `` represent actual occupancy '' , but determined to leave them out of consideration on the basis that `` they do not represent a source of repeat or recommended business as would conventional occupants '' .", "articleId": 1486, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Haberman", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Haberman", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "It said that prima facie the BCS invoices appeared to be dishonest documents , that Price Waterhouse -LRB- in the person of Mr Lee -RRB- had been unable to think of any other explanation for them and that , although Royal Hotel had sought to distinguish the Consolidator invoices , `` they are very similar , and your clients have declined to provide any details to support their suggestion that Consolidator received significant consideration for the charges made to it '' .", "articleId": 1490, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Lee", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Lee", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Royal Hotel \\ 's points of defence and counterclaim served 24th March 1994 pleaded -LRB- in what was then paragraph 18.17 -RRB- that Mr McHugh had in mid-June 1991 instructed Mr Anquetil to raise invoices to Consolidator in the sum of \\ xc2 \\ xa3150 ,000 at the rate of \\ xc2 \\ xa350 ,000 per month for the following three months , that during January to August 1991 the hotel had provided accommodation for contractors \\ ' staff working on Havilland Hall and the hotel on behalf of Royal Hotel and other group companies and that `` The sum of \\ xc2 \\ xa3150 ,000 was a reasonable sum for this accommodation '' .", "articleId": 1498, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "After letters from them and Sir Patrick , Herbert Smith responded on 12th October 1994 : '' Material Damage Award We are content that this should be dealt with in the manner proposed .", "articleId": 1504, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Patrick", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Patrick", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Sir Patrick thought it ambiguous whether they were concurring simply in a second interim award or also in its being in Royal Hotel \\ 's favour , but Herbert Smith did not respond to his request of 18th October 1994 seeking this clarification .", "articleId": 1505, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Patrick", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Patrick", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr McHugh \\ 's statement confirmed that the contractors \\ ' workmen had been housed in staff accommodation -LRB- Ypres Guest House , Kingslynn and Fermoy -RRB- and other guest houses , and not therefore in the rooms shown in the Consolidator invoices .", "articleId": 1512, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "McHugh", "em2Text": "Fermoy", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Fermoy", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "A letter from Herbert Smith to Royal Insurance of the same date recorded that the thinking behind this was , first , that insurers had good prospects of a better discount on taxation , secondly , that agreement on costs might simply provide Royal Hotel with a fighting fund for the impending trial of the `` fraud '' -LRB- i.e .", "articleId": 1525, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "entered into , as Mr McHugh and , by him , Royal Hotel knew at the time of the transactions , to mislead Royal Hotel \\ 's bankers as to the state of its balance sheer and/or -LRB- b -RRB- they included figures relating to the BCS and Consolidator transactions , which in whole or in part did not represent any or any real occupancy of the hotel and/or did not represent occupancy of the hotel in the ordinary course of its business as a hotel .", "articleId": 1529, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "McHugh", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "At the end of January 1996 Royal Hotel served supplementary statements from Mr McHugh and Mr Anquetil in the 1994 action .", "articleId": 1531, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "McHugh", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "McHugh", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "In the light of my judgment , insurers and Herbert Smith took independent expert advice on materiality , discussed materiality , inducement and the prospects of Royal Hotel establishing affirmation , decided to avoid the material damage insurance and on 12th August 1996 wrote accordingly .", "articleId": 1540, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "On the evidence , Herbert Smith have for several decades been regularly engaged by Royal Insurance to handle most of their large and high profile claims , as well as policy interpretation and litigious matters .", "articleId": 1542, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The relationship is one of closeness and considerable confidence , in which Royal Hotel looked to Herbert Smith when they wanted the highest quality of legal assistance .", "articleId": 1543, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Royal Insurance , which instructed Herbert Smith on behalf of both itself and ICCI , thus relied upon Herbert Smith to look after the interests of insurers during the arbitrations and the preparation for the 1994 trial and , as Mr Carter confirmed , to make judgments that required to be made during their course .", "articleId": 1544, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Carter", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Carter", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 3, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Carter", "start": 4, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "No suggestion has been made that any knowledge which may have been possessed or decision which may have been taken by Herbert Smith was not or should not be attributed for any relevant purposes to both ICCI and Royal Insurance .", "articleId": 1546, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 2, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Mr Bakes \\ 's statement , which was adduced as his evidence in chief , described how a question-mark arose over the `` honesty '' of the BCS transactions as a result of their reversal in Royal Hotel \\ 's accounts in late June 1993 , Mr Lee \\ 's advice that he could not think of an honest explanation and a comment by counsel for Royal Hotel in the arbitration that they had taken place `` in order to boost the revenue of the Royal Hotel '' .", "articleId": 1562, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Lee", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Lee", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The gist of Mr Bakes \\ ' account in paragraphs 47-48 was that Herbert Smith were troubled that the factual position remained unclear ; a distinction was still drawn between the BCS invoices and supported by KPMG ; they had formed the view that they were dealing with untrustworthy people at Royal Hotel , but they recognized a danger that they might be allowing essentially personal and instinctive reactions to get in the way of providing objective and dispassionate advice ; all the relevant evidence was in Royal Hotel \\ 's hands and they knew that the burden of proving fraud was a heavy one .", "articleId": 1578, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "KPMG", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}, {"em1Text": "KPMG", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "KPMG", "start": 1, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 2, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 3, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "Any communication with Royal Insurance on such a point would in practice have been by Mr Higgins .", "articleId": 1589, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Higgins", "em2Text": "Royal Insurance", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Royal Insurance", "start": 0, "label": "ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Higgins", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "He had a very vague recollection of Mr Higgins telling him at some point that he had mentioned the point to Mr Carter , but could give no time or detail .", "articleId": 1591, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Carter", "em2Text": "Higgins", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Higgins", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Carter", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "The phrase `` from that time as you know '' was explained by Mr Bakes as referring to his discussion with Mr Carter in early 1996 about Herbert Smith \\ 's thinking in November 1994 .", "articleId": 1608, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Herbert Smith", "em2Text": "Carter", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Carter", "start": 1, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 2, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "He recalled the discussion with Mr Higgins and Ms Kydd in November 1994 , and said that they had been concerned about the reliability of the information produced by Royal Hotel and had concluded -LRB- a -RRB- that they would only have all the relevant facts after judgment in the 1994 action and -LRB- b -RRB- that the right course would be to wait until then before deciding whether or not to assert non-disclosure in respect of the material damage policy , The affidavit continued : `` We decided that we were not in a position to amend the pleadings in the 1994 action , in relation to the business interruption policy .", "articleId": 1623, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Higgins", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Higgins", "start": 0, "label": "LOCATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "This was certainly Mr Carter \\ 's attitude when , a year later , the possibility of avoidance of the material damage policy was first discussed with him by Mr Higgins .", "articleId": 1643, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Carter", "em2Text": "Higgins", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Carter", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,LOCATION,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Higgins", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
{"sentText": "I find not only that Herbert Smith believed and on strong grounds that there had been such dishonesty , but that they did for present purposes `` know '' the real position , however much Royal Hotel continued to brazen it out with implausible denials or evasions .", "articleId": 1659, "relationMentions": [{"em1Text": "Royal Hotel", "em2Text": "Herbert Smith", "label": "None"}], "entityMentions": [{"text": "Herbert Smith", "start": 0, "label": "PERSON,ORGANIZATION"}, {"text": "Royal Hotel", "start": 1, "label": "LOCATION"}], "sentId": 0}
